<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Public on Mihir Pathak</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/public/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Public on Mihir Pathak</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Mihir Pathak (CC BY 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/public/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What motivates engineers?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-motivates-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-motivates-engineers/</guid>
      <description>I was listening to a podcast from Scaler called ScalerPod. Where they interview CTOs from different startups. They ask about their journey, challenges and how their typical day looks like.&#xA;Till now I have seen two episodes.&#xA;Kalish Nadh (CTO, Zerodha) Jacob Singh (CTO in Residence for Sequoia Capital in South East Asia and India)&#xA;I like both the episodes so much. Apart from tech both the episodes were filled with philosophies.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was listening to a podcast from Scaler called ScalerPod. Where they interview CTOs from different startups. They ask about their journey, challenges and how their typical day looks like.</p>
<p>Till now I have seen two episodes.</p>
<p>Kalish Nadh (CTO, Zerodha)
Jacob Singh (CTO in Residence for Sequoia Capital in South East Asia and India)</p>
<p>I like both the episodes so much. Apart from tech both the episodes were filled with philosophies. Here I would like to share one thought shared by Jacob about motivation for the work.</p>
<p>He shared that intrinsic motivation for work comes from three things :</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Autonomy</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Mastry</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Connectedness / Purpose</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Here you go :</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QEZMSbeziEw&t=870s">14:30</a> What motivates engineers?</p>
<p><strong>Full episode :</strong></p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QEZMSbeziEw" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I resonate with this idea so much so sharing here as a self note :)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>supportive environment to flurish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/supportive-environment-to-flurish/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/supportive-environment-to-flurish/</guid>
      <description>It was raining. I was traveling from Vadodara to Padra by local bus. In front of me, some college students were talking about their final year project ideas.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;If madam had let us leave earlier, we would have reached home sooner in this rain.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to work on any project now. I gave such a great idea, but madam directly rejected it. Does that idea come in handy in such rain?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was raining. I was traveling from Vadodara to Padra by local bus. In front of me, some college students were talking about their final year project ideas.</p>
<p>&ldquo;If madam had let us leave earlier, we would have reached home sooner in this rain.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t want to work on any project now. I gave such a great idea, but madam directly rejected it. Does that idea come in handy in such rain? People who have empty cars are offering seats to others. If we create such an app, car owners will know who else needs a ride.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;No, but these types of apps are already there, right?&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Yes, but I&rsquo;m talking about a local app.
Another great idea was an app for men&rsquo;s customized clothes. But madam wouldn’t even listen to it. &quot;</p>
<p>&ldquo;I also suggested a game idea, and she did the same thing.&rdquo;</p>
<hr>
<p>Let’s stop judging these students&rsquo; ideas and talk about their college teacher instead.</p>
<ul>
<li>Instead of listening to the students&rsquo; ideas and giving constructive feedback, she directly rejects them, saying it’s not possible.</li>
<li>She insults students in class in front of everyone.</li>
</ul>
<p>This behavior crushes the self-esteem and confidence of the students. We need teachers who allow young people to share new ideas freely. When they receive support without fear, their creativity can flourish. Remember these young people are entrepreneur of tomorrow</p>
<p>#Entrepreneurialmindset #21stcenturyskills #coching</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hope</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/hope/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday evening one of our local khojis called me. She is studying in 10th grade and part of a local khoji program.&#xA;She called me to share that she is going to do ‘nature bingo’ and ‘web of life’ activity with her class as part of geography class.&#xA;Her teacher gave a task to explain some topics from the textbook in a hands-on manner. This girl took the opportunity to introduce the wonder of nature to her classmates.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday evening one of our local khojis called me.
She is studying in 10th grade and part of a local khoji program.</p>
<p>She called me to share that she is going to do ‘nature bingo’ and ‘web of life’ activity with her class as part of geography class.</p>
<p>Her teacher gave a task to explain some topics from the textbook in a hands-on manner.
This girl took the opportunity to introduce the wonder of nature to her classmates.</p>
<p>She made my day by sharing this.</p>
<p>This is the butterfly effect for me</p>
<p>If you provide a locally relevant direct experiences + provide safe space to flourish
Young people can do wonders.</p>
<p>Local khoji and many many other organization and initiatives working with youth, environment, citizenship - are BIG hope for me.</p>
<p>hashtag#natureeducation hashtag#localkhoji hashtag#learningwala</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can I build something which helps young people thrive ?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-can-i-build-something-which-helps-young-people-thrive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-can-i-build-something-which-helps-young-people-thrive/</guid>
      <description>How can I build something which helps young people thrive ? What helped me? What are the key differentiators which help to achieve escape velocity ? What enables people to live a self - directed life ? if we see youth as change makers, citizens and future of india then we need to support young people&#xA;to achieve the skills they need for this rapidly changing world, community and belongingness</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>How can I build something which helps young people thrive ?</li>
<li>What helped me?</li>
<li>What are the key differentiators which help to achieve escape velocity ?</li>
<li>What enables people to live a self - directed life ?</li>
</ul>
<p>if we see youth as change makers, citizens and future of india then we need to support young people</p>
<p>to achieve the skills they need for this rapidly changing world, community and belongingness</p>
<p>think about the 16 year old boy or girl from small city like Vadodara, middle class family</p>
<ul>
<li>got typical education from school</li>
<li>no idea what career options / study options are available apart from typical sci, commerce and arts streams</li>
<li>no self confidence, very little self worth, no particular interests or ambition</li>
<li>easily get influenced by advertisements and media. No critical thinking lens</li>
</ul>
<p>In my journey what are the differentiators ?</p>
<p>the foundation is same but,</p>
<p>I got the opportunity to work on real life projects
I met people + spaces who don&rsquo;t judge, believe in you and give you the platform. Which ultimately become my tribe / community</p>
<p>How can I create this for friends and peers in Vadodara and my hometown Padra ?</p>
<p>Can project based learning become a starting point ?</p>
<p>Do one research / making / solving/entrepreneurship project around your city. Your questions, your ideas.</p>
<p>I will connect you with subject matter expert, will fund your project, will connect you with further opportunity  (internship / course / job / funding / learning)</p>
<p>This gives you non judgemental space, self confidence, you work in team, express yourself creatively and much more.</p>
<p>after the project done you becomes part of khoji community and keep doing interesting stuff</p>
<p>we will try to guide you for career opportunity, other learning opportunities</p>
<p>Local khoji is a distillation of ideas which I have been dreaming of for years.
Give unconventional, transformative learning experience to children.</p>
<p>This is not a CSR project / Not a NGO, it is just an initiative. I am very much open for collaboration
I am ready to share all my learnings / ideas / support  if you want to start local khoji at your town, your org, your school, your community. It can fit in your existing programs, curriculum and timetables.</p>
<p>contact - <a href="mailto:learningwalamihir@gmail.com">learningwalamihir@gmail.com</a></p>
<p>hashtag#natureeducation hashtag#projectbasedlearning hashtag#selfdirectedlearning</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Database of Inspirational Organizations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/database-of-inspirational-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/database-of-inspirational-organizations/</guid>
      <description>Here is your list of organizations working in youth development, life skills, active citizenship, civic-environment problem solving, self-directed learning, student agency, project-based learning, and vocational training, formatted in Markdown:&#xA;Database of Inspirational Organizations 1. Pravah Focuses on nurturing leadership and social responsibility among youth.&#xA;Pravah 2. ComMutiny - The Youth Collective Aims to create a supportive ecosystem for youth-led social change.&#xA;ComMutiny 3. Reap Benefit Engages young people in solving local civic and environmental issues.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here is your list of organizations working in youth development, life skills, active citizenship, civic-environment problem solving, self-directed learning, student agency, project-based learning, and vocational training, formatted in Markdown:</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="database-of-inspirational-organizations">Database of Inspirational Organizations</h3>
<h3 id="1-pravah">1. Pravah</h3>
<p>Focuses on nurturing leadership and social responsibility among youth.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.pravahindia.org/">Pravah</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="2-commutiny---the-youth-collective">2. ComMutiny - The Youth Collective</h3>
<p>Aims to create a supportive ecosystem for youth-led social change.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://commutiny.in/">ComMutiny</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="3-reap-benefit">3. Reap Benefit</h3>
<p>Engages young people in solving local civic and environmental issues.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.reapbenefit.org/">Reap Benefit</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="4-udhyam-learning-foundation">4. Udhyam Learning Foundation</h3>
<p>Promotes entrepreneurial and career skills among students and young adults.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.udhyam.org/">Udhyam Learning Foundation</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="5-land-a-hand-india">5. Land a Hand India</h3>
<p>Provides vocational training and career guidance to school students.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://lendahandindia.org/">Land a Hand India</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="6-synergy-sansthan">6. Synergy Sansthan</h3>
<p>Works towards youth empowerment and community development.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.synergysansthan.org/">Synergy Sansthan</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="7-project-defy">7. Project DEFY</h3>
<p>Empowers communities to create their own learning spaces called Nooks.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.projectdefy.org/">Project DEFY</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="8-kranti">8. Kranti</h3>
<p>Supports girls from marginalized backgrounds to become agents of social change.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.kranti-india.org/">Kranti</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="9-manzil">9. Manzil</h3>
<p>An educational center that provides supplementary learning and creative opportunities to underprivileged youth.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.manzil.in/">Manzil</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="10-creativity-adda">10. Creativity Adda</h3>
<p>Encourages creative learning and expression among children and youth.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.creativityadda.org/">Creativity Adda</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="11-swaraj-university">11. Swaraj University</h3>
<p>Focuses on self-designed learning paths for students seeking alternative education.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.swarajuniversity.org/">Swaraj University</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="12-dream-a-dream">12. Dream a Dream</h3>
<p>Provides life skills and empowerment programs for disadvantaged children and youth.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.dreamadream.org/">Dream a Dream</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="13-city-as-lab">13. City as Lab</h3>
<p>Engages students in city-based projects to learn about urban issues and solutions.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cityaslabindia.org/">City as Lab</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="14-young-climate-authors">14. Young Climate Authors</h3>
<p>Encourages youth to write and advocate for climate action.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.cogitation.in/educator-training-for-climate-authors">Young Climate Authors</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="15-involve-edu">15. Involve Edu</h3>
<p>Works to transform education by involving senior students in teaching their juniors.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.involveedu.com/">Involve Edu</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="16-eklavya-foundation---chakmak-club">16. Eklavya Foundation - Chakmak Club</h3>
<p>Promotes quality education and literacy in rural India.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.eklavya.in/">Eklavya Foundation</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="17-eklavya-india-foundation">17. Eklavya India Foundation</h3>
<p>Focuses on educational innovation and community empowerment.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://eklavyaindia.org/">Eklavya India Foundation</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="18-traveler-university">18. Traveler University</h3>
<p>Aims to provide experiential and community-based learning opportunities.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.travellersuniversity.org/">Traveler University</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="19-sahje-sapne">19. Sahje Sapne</h3>
<p>Empowers rural young women through education and skill-building programs.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://sajhesapne.org/">Sahje Sapne</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="20-oasis-valley-chanod">20. Oasis Valley, Chanod</h3>
<p>Provides transformative learning experiences in a natural setting.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.oasisvalley.org/">Oasis Valley</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="21-navgurukulam">21. Navgurukulam</h3>
<p>Focuses on providing free education and skill development to underprivileged youth.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.navgurukul.org/">Navgurukulam</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="22-restless-development">22. Restless Development</h3>
<p>A youth-led development agency working globally to empower young people.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://restlessdevelopment.org/">Restless Development</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="23-video-volunteers">23. Video Volunteers</h3>
<p>Trains community members to create and share videos about social issues.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.videovolunteers.org/">Video Volunteers</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="24-cube---hbcse">24. CUBE - HBCSE</h3>
<p>Collaborates on research and development in biology education.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.hbcse.tifr.res.in/research/past-projects/cube">CUBE - HBCSE</a></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>Feel free to explore these organizations for more information and inspiration in the field of youth development and education.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working with Youth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/working-with-youth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/working-with-youth/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 11 years now working in the education sector. I worked with children age 3yrs to 18yrs. Schools from state board to IB boards. Homeschooling groups and alternative schools too..&#xA;for the last few years I got interested in working with teenagers or youth.&#xA;How to give a platform to youth to thrive ? How to give opportunities where they can build their agency how they can be self directed learner and foster life skills how they engage in local environment and civic problems These are some of my goals when I say working with youth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been 11 years now working in the education sector. I worked with children age 3yrs to 18yrs. Schools from state board to IB boards. Homeschooling groups and alternative schools too..</p>
<p>for the last few years I got interested in working with teenagers or youth.</p>
<ul>
<li>How to give a platform to youth to thrive ?</li>
<li>How to give opportunities where they can build their agency</li>
<li>how they can be self directed learner and foster life skills</li>
<li>how they engage in local environment and civic problems</li>
</ul>
<p>These are some of my goals when I say working with youth.</p>
<p>As a self -directed learner I saw that you need two very strong pillars to build your journey.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>non judgmental safe space + mentor/friend/peers who can challenge you, give reflective tools to you. Basically your tribe, who trust you, believe in you no matter how good you are.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Exposure, Projects, Challenges, Things which helps you to shift your orbit
These are the two main things which I believe are game changers. I saw multiple organizations working on the same design.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>I want to spend the next 10 years of my life on this problem. What will be my intervention design ?</p>
<ul>
<li>can we design a program where children can do real life project</li>
<li>where children can opportunity to think, work in team, find mentors and more</li>
</ul>
<p>What should be the context ? Theme ?</p>
<p>Can we give the local environment and civic as a theme ?
If you merge it all together :</p>
<p>Local khoji - a platform for children to conduct original and authentic inquiry projects about the cities they live in.</p>
<p>Children can different type of projects - research projects, making projects, story project rooted in place they live.</p>
<p>This will be a 3 to 4 month journey, according to how much time school / NGO / learning centers give to work on the project.</p>
<p>This program design is very much inspired by Solve Ninja (Reap Benefit) and City as lab - Mumbai (@cityaslabindia)</p>
<p>What happened after this intervention ? children who were involved in can start a club called ‘Khoji club’ which will become a incubator / Adda kind of place for children. There will be different events happening, reading - making - movie screening - talks and lots of fun.</p>
<p>I want to make the whole process open source so anybody can run local khoji and khoji clubs at their own place. And I want to focus on more innovative ideas. I don’t want to run as a typical NGO / org but more like a laboratory where I constantly work on ideas to re imagine learning.</p>
<p>#citizenscience #natureeducation #projectbasedlearning</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights from ASER - Beyond Basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/insights-from-aser---beyond-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/insights-from-aser---beyond-basics/</guid>
      <description>Recently I read the ASER ‘Byond Basics’ report. It is all about young adults age 14 to 18yrs&#xA;Do they have technology access / smart phone What are their aspirations Can they read and do basic maths All these questions will give a window to a world of possibilities. How are they using smartphones and for what purpose ? Do they use it for learning ? If not, how can we encourage them to do that?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently I read the <a href="https://asercentre.org/aser-2023-beyond-basics/">ASER ‘Byond Basics’</a> report. It is all about young adults age 14 to 18yrs</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Do they have technology access / smart phone </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are their aspirations </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Can they read and do basic maths </p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>All these questions will give a window to a world of possibilities. How are they using smartphones and for what purpose ? Do they use it for learning ? If not, how can we encourage them to do that?</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Smartphones are a great equlazirer but contentwise we are competing with youtube. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What type of content we should publish in this situation </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Can we ask youth what they want?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How are you looking at learning happening outside the school ?</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>These all are questions to the window of possibilities. I read the report and some other articles. I am writing some insights which I got reflecting on them. </p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>We need to have dialgue with youth about what they want </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Only creating content and putting it in the air will not work, we need to make the whole ecosystem of learning.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We can blame or expect schools to teach everything we need to look at the needs of this age group outside the school structure. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We need to create informal learning spaces where young people can come, talk, and explore freely. (The youth wants a space to share their feelings, anxieties, and fears about the future.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Second step can be nudging them for some learning - challenging activities where smartphones or technology can play a bigger role. But that one on one connect, guidance, mentorship is important </p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Let’s take one scenario : </p>
<p>You started one youth program where young people join and teach children. Through this program you started one ‘youth adda’ where young people can come freely to talk - hangout. </p>
<p>Slowly you made genuine friendship with them, now they are open for your ideas and guidance.</p>
<p>You suggested they do one short course on ‘financial literacy’ so they can manage their finances well. Now high quilty content is important.</p>
<p>Youtube is winning because it is no brainer. You don’t need to think to see insta reels or youtube shots. You need brain, motivation and many other factors to see ‘learning content’</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>One way is, make your learning content in format of shots and influncere kind of videos. Like Vlogs and more. There are chances that you need to dilute your content to add those types of mirch masala.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Second way is to build an ecosystem which encourages and nudges us to explore ‘learning content’ apart from those nobrainers.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Let’s talk about Ankur wariku. He is making videos on financial literacy. Apart from making videos he is doing insta live with people to help them to learn ‘how to invest in their given salary’</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>He is building a community. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>He is taking subjects which very very relevant to young people </p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I believe we need to do both things in balance. We need to make our content more engaging and on the other side we need to build an ecosystem around it. </p>
<p>There are some more insights about vocational training and basic reading and maths </p>
<p>Which I will write some other time. </p>
<p><strong>Two very interesting panel discussions :</strong> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=13a8qGsXVYQ">Panel Discussion: ASER 2023 &lsquo;Beyond Basics&rsquo;</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2GkXMDaBGhI">Digital access and skills among youth | Evidence from ASER 2023 | ASER Centre &amp; EkStep Foundation</a></p>
<p><strong>Orgs which inspires me in the field of active citizenship and work with youth :</strong> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.pravahindia.org/">Pravah</a> </p>
<p><a href="https://commutiny.in/">Comutiny - Youth Collective</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.reapbenefit.org/">Reap Benfits</a> (<a href="https://idronline.org/article/youth/staying-relevant-how-organisations-can-support-todays-youth/">Wonderful article - staying-relevant-how-organisations-can-support-todays-youth/</a>)</p>
<p><a href="https://sajhesapne.org/">Shaje Sapne</a> </p>
<p><a href="https://www.aagaaztheatre.org/">Aagaz thetare</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Podcast / Courses / Blogs </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/interesting-podcast-courses-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/interesting-podcast-courses-blogs/</guid>
      <description>These are some podcasts / courses / blogs I go and explore frequently. I will keep adding new things here as I discover them.&#xA;Philosophy &amp;amp; Ideas by Anand Gandhi Memetics, Films, Storyteeling, evolutionary biology, Game Theory, PhilosophyLecture Collection | Human Behavioral Biology - Robert Sapolsky Free will, Behavioral Biology Philosophy &amp;amp; Ideas by Paras Chpra Podcast&#xA;Website/blog&#xA;Biology, Startup, AI, Philosophy, Science, MoneyJubin&amp;rsquo;s Blog PhilosophyThejesh GN Blog FOSS, Open Data, Open Street MapKartik Mistry Blog FOSS, Linux, Wikipedia, GujaratiEI Diloge NGO, CSR, Education Reform, Work at Scale</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These are some podcasts / courses / blogs I go and explore frequently. I will keep adding new things here as I discover them.</p>
<h3 id="philosophy--ideas-by-anand-gandhihttpswwwyoutubecomplaylistlistplf5poopyvc5ty7ajqcl4xsjpcav-uk_7w"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLf5poopYVc5Ty7AJQcL4xsJPCav-UK_7w">Philosophy &amp; Ideas by Anand Gandhi</a></h3>





<pre tabindex="0"><code>Memetics, Films, Storyteeling, evolutionary biology, Game Theory, Philosophy</code></pre><h3 id="lecture-collection--human-behavioral-biology---robert-sapolskyhttpswwwyoutubecomplaylistlistpl848f2368c90ddc3d"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL848F2368C90DDC3D">Lecture Collection | Human Behavioral Biology - Robert Sapolsky</a></h3>





<pre tabindex="0"><code>Free will, Behavioral Biology </code></pre><h3 id="philosophy--ideas-by-paras-chpra">Philosophy &amp; Ideas by Paras Chpra</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLf5poopYVc5T8wNOcuapPVszayqsvN-6d">Podcast</a></p>
<p><a href="https://invertedpassion.com/">Website/blog</a></p>





<pre tabindex="0"><code>Biology, Startup, AI, Philosophy, Science, Money</code></pre><h3 id="jubins-bloghttpsjubinsblogcom"><a href="https://jubinsblog.com/">Jubin&rsquo;s Blog</a></h3>





<pre tabindex="0"><code>Philosophy</code></pre><h3 id="thejesh-gn-bloghttpsthejeshgncom"><a href="https://thejeshgn.com/">Thejesh GN Blog</a></h3>





<pre tabindex="0"><code>FOSS, Open Data, Open Street Map</code></pre><h3 id="kartik-mistry-bloghttpskartikmwordpresscom"><a href="https://kartikm.wordpress.com/">Kartik Mistry Blog</a></h3>





<pre tabindex="0"><code>FOSS, Linux, Wikipedia, Gujarati</code></pre><h3 id="ei-dilogehttpswwwyoutubecomplaylistlistpl6ejv4-csfcfflethrp5emfdmznhagvz7"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6EJV4-csFcffLethrp5EmfdmzNHagVZ7">EI Diloge</a></h3>





<pre tabindex="0"><code>NGO, CSR, Education Reform, Work at Scale</code></pre>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>जड़ - पत्ति - बीज - फूल और हम</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%9C---%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%A4%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%A4%E0%A4%BF---%E0%A4%AC%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%9C---%E0%A4%AB%E0%A5%82%E0%A4%B2-%E0%A4%94%E0%A4%B0-%E0%A4%B9%E0%A4%AE/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/%E0%A4%9C%E0%A5%9C---%E0%A4%AA%E0%A4%A4%E0%A5%8D%E0%A4%A4%E0%A4%BF---%E0%A4%AC%E0%A5%80%E0%A4%9C---%E0%A4%AB%E0%A5%82%E0%A4%B2-%E0%A4%94%E0%A4%B0-%E0%A4%B9%E0%A4%AE/</guid>
      <description>Resources to introduce children to the world of leafs - seeds - roots - flowers - biodiversity around us&#xA;भाँति-भाँति की पत्तियाँ (Picture Book)&#xA;पत्तियों से जान-पहचान (Module)&#xA;जड़ - पत्ति - बीज (Module)&#xA;फूलो से जान पहचान (Module)&#xA;पौधों में प्रजनन (Module)&#xA;पौधों में पोषण (Module)&#xA;बीज और उनका अंकुरण (Module)&#xA;बीज का बिखरना (Module)&#xA;जीव जगत में विविधता (Module)&#xA;Source - Eklavya Foundation, Storyweaver</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Resources to introduce children to the world of leafs - seeds - roots - flowers - biodiversity around us</p>
<p><a href="https://storyweaver.org.in/en/stories/267499-bhaanti-bhaanti-kee-pattiyaan">भाँति-भाँति की पत्तियाँ</a> (Picture Book)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eklavya.in/pdfs/Books/HSTP/Bal_Vaigyanik_Current_Edition/Bal_Vaigyanik_Kaksha_6_Hindi/03_Pattiyon_Se_Jaan_Pehchan.pdf">पत्तियों से जान-पहचान</a> (Module)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eklavya.in/pdfs/Books/HSTP/Bal_Vaigyanik_Current_Edition/Bal_Vaigyanik_Kaksha_6_Hindi/11_Jad_Patti_aur_Beej.pdf">जड़ - पत्ति - बीज</a> (Module)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eklavya.in/pdfs/Books/HSTP/Bal_Vaigyanik_Current_Edition/Bal_Vaigyanik_Kaksha_7_Hindi/03_Phoolon_se_jan_pehchan.pdf">फूलो से जान पहचान</a> (Module)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eklavya.in/pdfs/Books/HSTP/Bal_Vaigyanik_Current_Edition/Bal_Vaigyanik_Kaksha_7_Hindi/06_Poudhon_me_prajanan.pdf">पौधों में प्रजनन </a> (Module)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eklavya.in/pdfs/Books/HSTP/Bal_Vaigyanik_Current_Edition/Bal_Vaigyanik_Kaksha_7_Hindi/21_Poudhon_mei_poshan.pdf">पौधों में पोषण </a> (Module)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eklavya.in/pdfs/Books/HSTP/Bal_Vaigyanik_Current_Edition/Bal_Vaigyanik_Kaksha_6_Hindi/08_Beej_aur_Unka_Ankuran.pdf">बीज और उनका अंकुरण </a> (Module)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eklavya.in/pdfs/Books/HSTP/Bal_Vaigyanik_Current_Edition/Bal_Vaigyanik_Kaksha_6_Hindi/09_Beejo_ka_Bikharna.pdf">बीज का बिखरना </a> (Module)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eklavya.in/pdfs/Books/HSTP/Bal_Vaigyanik_Current_Edition/Bal_Vaigyanik_Kaksha_6_Hindi/16_Jeevjagat_Me_Vividhta.pdf">जीव जगत में विविधता </a> (Module)</p>
<p>Source - <a href="https://eklavya.in/">Eklavya Foundation</a>, <a href="https://storyweaver.org.in">Storyweaver</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I never bought a new laptop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/i-never-bought-a-new-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/i-never-bought-a-new-laptop/</guid>
      <description>I have never bought new laptop in my life. I had P4 computer at home around 2008 - 9 After that when I dropped out of school and started working in different organisation, people helped me with their old laptops.&#xA;My first laptop was Asuse eee pc. I was using it with Ubuntu &amp;amp; openSUSE later on..&#xA;Asuse eee pc with makey makey circuit&#xA;I remember going to Jigish Bhai&amp;rsquo;s office and making live USB boot for openSUSE Linux distro.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have never bought new laptop in my life. I had P4 computer at home around 2008 - 9
After that when I dropped out of school and started working in different organisation, people helped me with their old laptops.</p>
<p>My first laptop was <strong>Asuse eee pc</strong>. I was using it with <strong>Ubuntu &amp; openSUSE</strong> later on..</p>
<p><img alt="Asuse eee pc" src="/laptop/eee.png">
<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p>Asuse eee pc with <a href="https://makeymakey.com/">makey makey circuit</a></p>
<p>I remember going to Jigish Bhai&rsquo;s office and making live USB boot for openSUSE Linux distro. That was my first introduction to open source &amp; free software world. My mama Nirmal Pathak is fedora contributor. I remember reading Kartik Bhai&rsquo;s blog about debian &amp; Wikipedia. Doing wikipedia meetup at goraj muni seva ashram.</p>
<p>samyak bhai introduced me to markdown, git and world of developer :)</p>
<hr>
<p>When I went to dharampur few friends donated 2 - 3 laptops for our school.</p>
<ul>
<li>Toshiba - Vaibhav Pandya</li>
<li>Samsung - Jubin Mehta</li>
<li>Samsung (silver) - Shruti</li>
<li>ASUSE - chirag patel</li>
</ul>
<p>All the laptop were very old, their parts stopped working one by one (like screen, keyboard, battery, etc) accept Samsung (silver) one. When I went to Bhuj one visitor at our school gifted <strong>old macbook air 2013 model</strong>. It was in pretty good condition. I swapped samsung silver with that and started using it.</p>
<p>Since then I am using it as my primary machine. Writing, web browsing, teaching MIT Scratch to children, many other tinkering.. I changed the battery few months ago.</p>
<p><img alt="Macbook Air 2013" src="/laptop//mac.png">
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
( Macbook Air 2013 )</p>
<p>In 2021 Srishti gifted her old macbook air to me. I was using it with children on and off. When Nidhi needed laptop I gave it her. But unfortunately battery of that machine got swelled like balloon. It is difficult to open the body and change it.</p>
<p>Now I gave my macbook air to her and decided to buy new - refurbished laptop.</p>
<p>After some research 2 friends suggested to check out the work of Abhas Abhinav founder of Mostly harmless computers. He is FOSS enthusiast - activist - technologist - hardware hacker - geek. He runs a libretech.shop - a ethical source for libre and liberated hardware products.</p>
<p>I visited his office. It was nostalgia for me to dive in to the world of FOSS again. This time Nidhi was also there. I was happy to introduce her to this philosophy..</p>
<p><strong>Abhas bhai gifted me a book called &lsquo;code swaraj&rsquo; which is in my reading list.</strong></p>
<p><img alt="Code Swaraj" src="/laptop//book.jpeg">
<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p><strong>he also gifted mostlly harmless USB dive with around 13 type of linux distro</strong></p>
<p><img alt="Thinkpad X1 Carbon" src="/laptop//usb.jpeg">
<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p>From his recommendation I met Ved who runs refurbished laptop shop in banaswadi.
After so much of comparing and testing I finally bought refurbished Thinkpad X1 Carbon 6th Gen (Intel i7 8th Gen, 16GB RAM, 512 HDD)</p>
<p><img alt="Thinkpad X1 Carbon" src="/laptop//thinkpad.jpeg">
<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<h3 id="my-criteria-was">My criteria was</h3>
<ul>
<li>repairablity</li>
<li>possiblity to upgrade (RAM, CPU)</li>
<li>portabilty (light weight)</li>
<li>feature proof</li>
<li>compatable with linux / free bios</li>
</ul>
<p>Thinkpad X1C is not true for all criteria. Number 1 yes, 2 no , 3 big yes, 4 yes, 5 yes - linux can run very nicely but the bios is not free you can&rsquo;t do core boot. You can&rsquo;t upgrade RAM. But solution I am thinking is after 5 - 6 years of usage I can again sell it to refurbished shop and upgrade the machine.</p>
<p>Tjesh GN, Aditya, Kartik bhai, Nirmal bhai and Suchakra helped a lot take the disison. Thank you so much.</p>
<p>So <strong>welcome to family - Thinkpad X1 Carbon - 2nd March 2024</strong></p>
<p>During this process I read a lot about FOSS and again visited <a href="kartikm.wordpress.com">Kartik bhai</a> &amp; <a href="https://thejeshgn.com/">Thejesh&rsquo;s blog</a>. I amazed with the power of community in FOSS and really wish to see that in education sector.</p>
<hr>
<p><a href="https://mostlyharmless.io/">more about Abhas bhai / mostly harmless</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My blogging journey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-blogging-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>mihir@learningwala.in (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-blogging-journey/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1 I started my first blog around 2012 from one cyber cafe. It was very fascinating for me at that time.&#xA;I can put something on the computer and the whole world can see. More than blogging it was about the whole website technology was fascinating for me.&#xA;Instead of going to school I used to roam around different offices/ shops who make websites for small businesses. I visit them as customers and ask too many questions&amp;hellip; later on I did a market job with them in exchange for learning from their developer.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="chapter-1">Chapter 1</h2>
<p>I started my first blog around 2012 from one cyber cafe. It was very fascinating for me at that time.<br>
I can put something on the computer and the whole world can see. More than blogging it was about the whole website technology was fascinating for me.</p>
<p>Instead of going to school I used to roam around different offices/ shops who make websites for small businesses. I visit them as customers and ask too many questions&hellip; later on I did a market job with them in exchange for learning from their developer.</p>
<p>I learn about static - dynamic websites, CMS (wordpress, Dhrupal, Jhoomla), some basics about HTML CSS and PHP, what is domain, what is hosting and server. And most importantly how to do business of developing websites - profit margins and other stuff.</p>
<p>My first blog/website was called &lsquo;<strong>Pathak Technologies</strong>&rsquo;. Small web development firm<br>
it was on <strong>blogger/blogspot.com</strong></p>
<h2 id="chapter-2">Chapter 2</h2>
<p>Around 2013 I moved to wordpress. At that time there was a big Gujarati blogger community on wordpress. Most of them are sitting in the USA or Canada and blogging about their retired life :)<br>
I remember Suresh dada&rsquo;s blog, Vinod bhai blog&hellip;</p>
<p>I also remember reading <a href="https://hirals.wordpress.com/">Hiral ben</a>, <a href="https://kartikm.wordpress.com/">Kartik bhai</a>, <a href="https://nirmalpathak.wordpress.com/">Nirmal bhai&rsquo;s blogs</a>.</p>
<p>I was running three blogs at that time -</p>
<ul>
<li>my personal blog called &lsquo;<a href="https://mihirism.wordpress.com/">Mihirism</a>&rsquo;</li>
<li>blog called <a href="https://sureshbjani.wordpress.com/2013/10/24/laboratory/">&lsquo;Prayog Ghar&rsquo;</a> about science &amp; technology in simple language</li>
<li>&lsquo;<a href="https://kelavani.wordpress.com/">Sanistha kelavani</a>&rsquo; about Nai taleem education</li>
<li>I was contributing on &lsquo;<a href="http://evidyalay.net/">Evidyalay</a>&rsquo;</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="Medium" src="/blogging/medium.png">
<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p><em><strong>it was wonderful learning time</strong></em></p>
<h2 id="chapter-3">Chapter 3</h2>
<p>I remember samyak bhai introduced me to markdown, git and something called &lsquo;<a href="https://medium.com/">Medium</a>&rsquo; :)</p>
<p><em><strong>Medium was very new and silk that time. super clean writing focused blogging platform.</strong></em></p>
<p>I liked it immediately and made <a href="https://medium.com/@learningwala">my profile</a>. <strong>My last post on Medium was on Nov- 2023</strong></p>
<p>I wrote about my classroom experiences / learning experiments with children and teachers, I wrote about some interesting resources I found for educators / interesting stuff around pedagogy and more. mostly centred around education, philosophy and pedagogy . Sometimes some personal stuff like poems or life as an educator..</p>
<p><strong>in between, around 2015</strong></p>
<p>we (<a href="https://www.lakhan.me/">lakhan samani</a> and <a href="https://github.com/kash9350">kashyap</a> helped me a lot. very grateful for that - Thank you guys) have made &rsquo;learnlabs&rsquo; website in PHP</p>
<p><strong>Around 2018</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://jubinsblog.com/">Jubin</a> introduced me to wix.com - I made first version on &rsquo;learningwala.com&rsquo; on that</p>
<p><strong>I was using it till 2022</strong></p>
<p>During that time I shifted my blogging journey on <a href="https://instagram.com/learningwala">instagram</a>.</p>
<p>Mostly because I was getting community over there. Educators, Artist and more. I mostly put posts about my experiments with children, workshops I am conducting with teachers, books I am reading, inspiring educators and more.</p>
<p><strong>till now 839 posts, 1132 followers</strong></p>
<p>oh, I forgot about facebook. I have been active on FB since 2010 (Remember UC Browser ??) till I got instagram. After instagram, facebook is running on auto pilot. All instagram posts auto publish on FB.</p>
<p>I tried IFTTT before this instagram feature came.</p>
<ul>
<li>I made some very good connections through <a href="https://instagram.com/learningwala">instagram</a> and facebook.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="chapter-4">Chapter 4</h2>
<p>After leaving wix for my personal website I shifted my stuff (projects, writing, CV, etc) on <a href="https://linktr.ee/learningwala">linktree</a>.</p>
<p>I made websites for friends on wix and still maintain it.</p>
<p>Since the last few months I have had the desire to start my blogging journey again. With more categories in writing like weekly notes, ideas for project based learning / nature based learning and some other experiments.</p>
<p><strong>Medium is now paid for. You can&rsquo;t read unlimited stories.</strong> I started exploring other platforms<br>
Ghost, Wordpress, there is a long list of minimal blogging platforms. Some are giving self hosting facilities.</p>
<p>I was looking for a super minimal platform where I can just write posts and I have control on my data.<br>
no advertisement, monetisation of posts, no social network around blog, - just writing place</p>
<p>Someone suggested trying <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> and Github pages. It was too geeky for me. I tried two - three themes but never started writing on it.</p>
<p>I found something called <a href="bearblog.dev">bearblog.dev</a></p>
<p>Basically, someone developed a back-end to update your static site. It is perfect for minimal blogging<br>
but it is not available for self hosting, what if this project got stopped ? What if the product strategy of this platform changes ?</p>
<p>But I really like the theme. I searched more and luckily I found the same theme on github which was available self hosting on <a href="https://pages.github.com/">github pages</a> / <a href="https://www.netlify.com/">netlify</a> / your own server.</p>
<p>Finally I saw two youtube videos and learned how to set it. <strong>And yes I am writing on the same platform :)</strong></p>
<h2 id="low-tech-website">Low tech website</h2>
<p><em>This website too simple, ugly, no modern features</em></p>
<p>And no Js, No cookies, no tracker, fast, clean, functional, you own the data, you can develop in your own ways, less energy usage, less computing power usage</p>
<p><strong>let&rsquo;s find why, what and How about low tech website :</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.resilience.org/stories/2018-09-27/how-to-build-a-low-tech-website/">- How to Build a Low-tech Website?</a></p>
<p><a href="https://lente.dev/en/posts/stone-websites/">- Stone websites</a></p>
<p><a href="https://jeffhuang.com/designed_to_last/">- This Page is Designed to Last</a></p>
<p><strong>My ultimate dream is to host my own static site on solar powered raspberry pi<br>
someday I will do it for sure.</strong></p>
<p>Thank you</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
