<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Privet on Mihir Pathak | મિહિર પાઠક</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/privet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privet on Mihir Pathak | મિહિર પાઠક</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>learningwalamihir@gmail.com (Mihir Pathak)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>learningwalamihir@gmail.com (Mihir Pathak)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Mihir Pathak (CC BY 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/privet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 1/2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-1-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>learningwalamihir@gmail.com (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-1-2025/</guid>
      <description>28th Dec 2024 to 4th Jan 2025 (Saturday to Saturday) During Jan 2024 to Dec 2024 me and Nidhi did worked with different groups of children, facilitated worskhops, orgnized residential camps and more. I tried to capture all our activities in one photo report - Gulmohar I wrote 2024 year end reflections I wanted to work with young people for so long. I wanted to design fellowship kind of program where they get opportunity to work on real life projects, travel, meet people outside of their circle.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4 id="28th-dec-2024-to-4th-jan-2025-saturday-to-saturday">28th Dec 2024 to 4th Jan 2025 (Saturday to Saturday)</h4>
<ul>
<li>During Jan 2024 to Dec 2024 me and Nidhi did worked with different groups of children, facilitated worskhops, orgnized residential camps and more. I tried to capture all our activities in one photo report - <a href="https://www.canva.com/design/DAGaq8utmtg/O439oGkID5vYzoAcNmCFkQ/view?utm_content=DAGaq8utmtg&utm_campaign=designshare&utm_medium=link2&utm_source=uniquelinks&utlId=h2c229f4669#1">Gulmohar</a></li>
<li>I wrote <a href="https://learningwala.in/blog/2024-reflections/">2024 year end reflections</a></li>
<li>I wanted to work with young people for so long. I wanted to design fellowship kind of program where they get opportunity to work on real life projects, travel, meet people outside of their circle. Finally it worked out. Friends from sai&rsquo;s angel foundation + Me &amp; Nidhi are working on something called sakha fellowship. We are launching it on 12th Jan. I spent time on developing all the ideas related to it.</li>
<li>My health went down, fever, low blood pressure</li>
<li>I am getting married on 4th Feb. Preparations are going in full swing. On 5th Jan relatives are going to come at home to write invitation card (Kankotri in Gujarati) so I helped parents to prepare for the same.</li>
<li>I did calculation of all funding and other money I have and how much I utilize in what.
Didn&rsquo;t get proper calculation for salary money (money apart from grant).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>

