<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>2025 on Mihir Pathak | મિહિર પાઠક</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/2025/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2025 on Mihir Pathak | મિહિર પાઠક</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <managingEditor>learningwalamihir@gmail.com (Mihir Pathak)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>learningwalamihir@gmail.com (Mihir Pathak)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Mihir Pathak (CC BY 4.0)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/2025/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 4/2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-4-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>learningwalamihir@gmail.com (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-4-2025/</guid>
      <description>19th to 25th Jan 2025 (Sunday to Saturday) Sunday : Mostly spent time in reading weekly notes from different people. I found out blog ring developed by Thejesh GN where he saved URLs of blogs with weekly notes. He also mentioned some new names of weekly note writers in his recent note. I got know about wonderful work of Adhavan Sivaraj from the weekly note section.&#xA;Monday : Worked on khojbeen logo myself, Antara wrote khojbeen by hand and sent a photo.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4 id="19th-to-25th-jan-2025-sunday-to-saturday">19th to 25th Jan 2025 (Sunday to Saturday)</h4>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sunday : Mostly spent time in reading weekly notes from different people. I found out <a href="https://thejeshgn.com/projects/blogring/">blog ring</a> developed by <a href="https://thejeshgn.com">Thejesh GN</a> where he saved URLs of blogs with weekly notes. He also mentioned some new names of weekly note writers in his recent <a href="https://thejeshgn.com/2025/01/17/weekly-notes-03-2025/">note</a>. I got know about wonderful work of <a href="https://adhavansivaraj.xyz">Adhavan Sivaraj</a> from the weekly note section.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Monday : Worked on khojbeen logo myself, Antara wrote khojbeen by hand and sent a photo. I used that photo and tried to make something on canva. I was very much impressed by the logo ALT EFF so I used background color of that. <a href="https://adityadipankar.com/">Aditya</a> gave some ideas.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><img alt="Khojbeen logo" src="/w4.2025/khojbeenlogos.png"></p>
<ul>
<li>Tuesday : First half went in office meetings,</li>
</ul>
<p>→ I got to know about amazing work of <a href="https://www.early-bird.in/meet-an-educator-nayantara-siruguri/">Canopy Collective &amp; educator Nayantra Siruguri</a> in Place based education</p>
<p>→ I read about <a href="https://explorers.nationalgeographic.org/directory/arshiya-urveeja-bose">arshiya bose</a> and her venture <a href="https://www.instagram.com/blackbazacoffee/?hl=en">Black Baza Coffee Co</a></p>
<p>→ 	I prepared for the first session I am going to facilutate for sakha fellowship. It is about biology of money. I refered podcast from <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gf09vjWp3E4&t=1s">anand gandhi and kunal shah</a>. I am very excited about this session, let&rsquo;s see how it goes. Suraj made wonderful poster for the same.</p>
<p><img alt="Poster" src="/w4.2025/biologyofmoneyposter.png"></p>
<p>→ On Monday I wrote an email to <a href="https://adhavansivaraj.xyz/">Adhvan</a> about exploring tools for river mapping and tree mapping. He promptly replied and me, Nidhi and Adhvan had call on Tuesday evening. We asked for 30min call and it streched for an hour.</p>
<p>→ We talked about each other&rsquo;s work, connection with weekly notes, blogs, funding, how can we collbrate and more.</p>
<p>→ He introduced some amazing apps for mapping specifically :</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>He introduce us to app called <a href="https://every-door.app/">every door</a> which is open street map based app. Where you can map trees, building and other catagories through your mobile directly on OSM. You will need OSM account for this.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://awana.digital/mapeo">Co Mapeo</a> - Mapeo is a free digital toolset for documenting, monitoring, and mapping many types of data.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://osmand.net/">OSM and</a> - Offline Maps and Navigation</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Wednesday :</li>
</ul>
<p>→ Day started with a short call with <a href="https://www.sriviliveshere.com/">Srivi</a>. It was long due. I was so happy that she remembered it and reached out. We talked about some collaboration opportunities :</p>
<ol>
<li>We can write academic paper around &lsquo;Development of environmental aesthetic sense development in Indian Context&rsquo;</li>
<li>Collaborating with master&rsquo;s student from <a href="https://srishtimanipalinstitute.in/">srishti</a> for their final project.</li>
<li>We also talked about how we tap in to grant / funding opportunities. May be <a href="https://www.instagram.com/ramnathchandrasekhar/">Ram</a> can help us in that. She also gave some ideas if I want to do masters / PhD kind of thing.</li>
</ol>
<p>→ She shared interesting document by <a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/environmental-aesthetics/">Arnold Berleant on Environmental Aesthetics</a></p>
<p>→ and a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gk9XlbKBeac">short film</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/srivi_connecting-with-natureconnecting-with-ourselves-activity-7287719386189086721-RPA4?utm_source=share&utm_medium=member_android">post</a> about her work with children in Chennai.</p>
<p>→ At DEFY, we started capacity building program for nook fellows.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 3/2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-3-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>learningwalamihir@gmail.com (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-3-2025/</guid>
      <description>11th to 18th Jan 2025 (Saturday to Saturday) Workshop with educators from different NGOs / learning centers | Sai&amp;rsquo;s Angel Foundation | 11th Jan 2025&#xA;Launch of the Sakha Fellowship | 12th Jan 2025&#xA;13th Jan : Dhara and Bharat went back to their home town.&#xA;14th Jan : me and Nidhi came to padra, celebrated Makarsankranti with family. It was first makarsankrati of Nidhi. She saw this type of festival, flying kites at this scale for first time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4 id="11th-to-18th-jan-2025-saturday-to-saturday">11th to 18th Jan 2025 (Saturday to Saturday)</h4>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DE0HQJvS3YC/?img_index=1">Workshop with educators from different NGOs / learning centers</a> | Sai&rsquo;s Angel Foundation | 11th Jan 2025</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DE0JwJXypmi/">Launch of the Sakha Fellowship</a> | 12th Jan 2025</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>13th Jan : Dhara and Bharat went back to their home town.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>14th Jan : me and Nidhi came to padra, celebrated Makarsankranti with family. It was first makarsankrati of Nidhi. She saw this type of festival, flying kites at this scale for first time.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>on 15th night nidhi needs to catch the train to Kanpur. She needs to do lots of packing. So mummy papa came to drop us at nidhi&rsquo;s place.</p>
<p>Nidhi requested that she need help in packing so I also went at her place.
whole day she did packing and I gave her a company.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>15th night mummy, papa, and me went to station to drop nidhi. Now we will directly meet her in marriage.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>16th Jan - in evening I have attended online call by Shishir bhai about current state of vishwamitri river and how we can do something about it. I am planning to write separate post about the same.You can get updates on this <a href="https://www.instagram.com/voicesofvishwamitri/">insta handle</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>17, 18 - mostly office work</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Some photos :</strong></p>
<figure><img src="/w3.2025/kite1.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="600" height="600"><figcaption>
      <p>Makarsankranti</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/w3.2025/kite2.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="600" height="600"><figcaption>
      <p>Makarsankranti</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>Vishwamitri River Meeting</strong></p>
<figure><img src="/w3.2025/vishwamitri.png"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="600"><figcaption>
      <p>VoV meeting</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>Received marriage gift from dear friend <a href="https://www.instagram.com/mukherjiantara_art/">Antara</a> from BLR - 17th Jan</strong></p>
<figure><img src="/w3.2025/gift1.png"
    alt="Description of the image" width="400" height="300"><figcaption>
      <p>Gift by Antara</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Me and Nidhi are thinking about giving proper name and visual identity to our nature education work. Learningwala is there but nidhi is feeling that, it is my brand and my work, she is not feeling that she is part of it. So we have decided to create something new which we both can hold and nurture.</p>
<p>I was thinking about different names.. KhojBeen Mandali suck to my mind. Nidhi also liked it. I started reaching out to people seeking help in visual identity. Rachita called me and gave some ideas about how to start. I had a chat with Ipsa Jain, Ashra, Nipun Prabhakar, Jinal, Chaitali and few other folks about the same.</p>
<figure><img src="/w3.2025/khojbeen.png"
    alt="Description of the image" width="800" height="600"><figcaption>
      <p>Msg to artist</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>Overall mood and other things</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Overall I am happy. Work at DEFY is going well.</li>
<li>I am happy that my and nidhi&rsquo;s friends are coming to our wedding</li>
<li>After eliminating all the options we have decided to go to <a href="https://www.ntpatelhighschool.org/">Mitali ben&rsquo;s school</a> from march. <a href="https://gopaldham.org/">Gopaldham</a> option is still open, today morning I had call with Varun. He is ready to accommodate both of us with salary we are expecting. The only thing is it is very remote area and we will feel alone. Here mitali ben is there, vadodra is near by so it will work out. I told varun that we will meet after 15th feb. We will visit the school so we can get idea.</li>
</ul>
<p>Mostly we will take a risk and go to Mitali ben&rsquo;s school :)</p>
<p><strong>Process of elimination :</strong></p>
<figure><img src="/w3.2025/page1.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="700"><figcaption>
      <p>Page 1</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/w3.2025/page2.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="700"><figcaption>
      <p>Page 2</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>Current Focus</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>DEFY work</li>
<li>Sakha Fellowship</li>
<li>Balvikas course</li>
<li>Wedding Prep</li>
<li>Khojbeen&hellip;</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 2/2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-2-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>learningwalamihir@gmail.com (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-2-2025/</guid>
      <description>4th to 11th Jan 2025 (Saturday to Saturday) 5th, 6th : home&#xA;7th : shopping, came to nidhi&amp;rsquo;s place&#xA;8th : gave interview to Anushree in the morning (Anushree Gokhale, a PhD candidate at M. S. University, Vadodara, conducting a critical study on well-being in Indian adults living in Gujarat. This research explores how life stages, work status, and beliefs like Karma-Yoga shape subjective well-being.More details here)&#xA;9th : Sakha lunch meeting.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4 id="4th-to-11th-jan-2025-saturday-to-saturday">4th to 11th Jan 2025 (Saturday to Saturday)</h4>
<ul>
<li>
<p>5th, 6th : home</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>7th : shopping, came to nidhi&rsquo;s place</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>8th : gave interview to Anushree in the morning (Anushree Gokhale, a PhD candidate at M. S. University, Vadodara, conducting a critical study on well-being in Indian adults living in Gujarat. This research explores how life stages, work status, and beliefs like Karma-Yoga shape subjective well-being.More details <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:7246708729927094272/">here</a>)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>9th : Sakha lunch meeting. We (Ashish bhai, Rameshwari ben, Nikita ben, Saurabh bhai, Nidhi, Mihir sajid bhai ) went to kathivadi darbar. it was super fun.
evening - went to gajra cafe (Anushree, Nidhi, Mihir). It was fun to roam around in old city. Eating raju patti samosa..</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>10th : Bharat and dhara came. We again went to gajara cafe, ate pavbhaji near sursagar..</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>they were student of alternative school near rajkot / chotila calle &lsquo;K shala&rsquo;. I use to do BA sociology from surastra university around 2017. During that time I use to visit this school. Bharat came to my place when I was working in Bhuj. I was so happy to see them after so many years. Our relationship was not like teacher - students. We are friends. I am so happy that they are now working with children and trying to create environment which they got during k shala. They also shared the updates about other students that they are doing well in their respective fields and some of them are getting married soon.</p>
<p>chetan is in ahemdabad running organic milk startup with Srishti (Prof Anil)
shailesh is working in nephropathy centers
Vibhu is also working in nisarg upchar kendra
Nikunj is not doing anything as per them :)
Deepak is working in factory
Harshad is interested in mountaineering and he is working as guide for different groups</p>
<p>Bharat and Dhara are going to work at shishukunj foundation, Bhuj. They are going to work with children from gov schools. Me &amp; Nidhi were thinking to visit them and do some nature education work with them. I felt that they are thinking limited scope of work like doing games and art activity with children. We can do lot more. We will talk to them. I it just thought, I never seen them working so I might be wrong.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iuUERwuUtFI">Here you can watch video about alternative school - ક શાળા</a></p>
<ul>
<li>11th : <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DE0HQJvS3YC/?img_index=1">Workshop with educators from different NGOs / learning centers</a> | Sai&rsquo;s Angel Foundation | 11th Jan 2025</li>
</ul>
<p>After the workshop Dhara, Bharat, Nidhi and me went to Kamati bag.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Photos</strong></p>
<p><strong>Gajara Cafe Photos 9th Jan</strong></p>
<figure><img src="/w2.2025/mihirandnidhi.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="400"><figcaption>
      <p>Mihir &amp; Nidhi at Gajra Cafe</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/w2.2025/gajracafe1.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="500"><figcaption>
      <p>Gajra Cafe</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/w2.2025/gajracafe2.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="700"><figcaption>
      <p>Gajra Cafe</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/w2.2025/gajracafe3.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="400"><figcaption>
      <p>Gajra Cafe</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/w2.2025/gajracafe4.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="700"><figcaption>
      <p>Near sursagar lake</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>Gathiya Breakfast on 10th Jan</strong></p>
<figure><img src="/w2.2025/gathiya.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="400"><figcaption>
      <p>Gathiya Breakfast on 10th Jan</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>Kamati bag on 11th Jan</strong></p>
<figure><img src="/w2.2025/kamatibag1.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="700"><figcaption>
      <p>Kamatibag</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><img src="/w2.2025/kamatibag2.jpeg"
    alt="Description of the image" width="500" height="400"><figcaption>
      <p>Kamatibag</p>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 1/2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-1-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>learningwalamihir@gmail.com (Mihir Pathak)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-1-2025/</guid>
      <description>28th Dec 2024 to 4th Jan 2025 (Saturday to Saturday) During Jan 2024 to Dec 2024 me and Nidhi did worked with different groups of children, facilitated worskhops, orgnized residential camps and more. I tried to capture all our activities in one photo report - Gulmohar I wrote 2024 year end reflections I wanted to work with young people for so long. I wanted to design fellowship kind of program where they get opportunity to work on real life projects, travel, meet people outside of their circle.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4 id="28th-dec-2024-to-4th-jan-2025-saturday-to-saturday">28th Dec 2024 to 4th Jan 2025 (Saturday to Saturday)</h4>
<ul>
<li>During Jan 2024 to Dec 2024 me and Nidhi did worked with different groups of children, facilitated worskhops, orgnized residential camps and more. I tried to capture all our activities in one photo report - <a href="https://www.canva.com/design/DAGaq8utmtg/O439oGkID5vYzoAcNmCFkQ/view?utm_content=DAGaq8utmtg&utm_campaign=designshare&utm_medium=link2&utm_source=uniquelinks&utlId=h2c229f4669#1">Gulmohar</a></li>
<li>I wrote <a href="https://learningwala.in/blog/2024-reflections/">2024 year end reflections</a></li>
<li>I wanted to work with young people for so long. I wanted to design fellowship kind of program where they get opportunity to work on real life projects, travel, meet people outside of their circle. Finally it worked out. Friends from sai&rsquo;s angel foundation + Me &amp; Nidhi are working on something called sakha fellowship. We are launching it on 12th Jan. I spent time on developing all the ideas related to it.</li>
<li>My health went down, fever, low blood pressure</li>
<li>I am getting married on 4th Feb. Preparations are going in full swing. On 5th Jan relatives are going to come at home to write invitation card (Kankotri in Gujarati) so I helped parents to prepare for the same.</li>
<li>I did calculation of all funding and other money I have and how much I utilize in what.
Didn&rsquo;t get proper calculation for salary money (money apart from grant).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
